[
    {
        "question": "Which design principle refers to the attribute of an object that intuitively indicates how it should be used?",
        "options": [
            "Constraints",
            "Affordance",
            "Visibility",
            "Feedback"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Calm technology that stays in the background and activates unobtrusively when needed\" is the definition of:",
        "options": [
            "GUI",
            "multimodal interface",
            "command-line interface",
            "ubiquitous computing"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "During the iterative design process:",
        "options": [
            "cycles of design-test-measure-redesign are repeated as often as necessary",
            "the number of design-test-measure-redesign cycles is decided prior",
            "the number of design-test-measure-redesign cycles is 3",
            "feedback and consequent refinement are taken into consideration only at the end of the development"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to labels, icons are:",
        "options": [
            "less visually attractive and distinctive",
            "easier to learn and remember",
            "able to represent only concrete objects",
            "larger and require more screen space"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "______ involves selecting things on which to concentrate, at a point in time, from the range of possibilities available:",
        "options": [
            "perception",
            "memory",
            "learning",
            "attention"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Questionnaires are a well-established technique:",
        "options": [
            "used for collecting demographic data and users' opinions",
            "used because the participants' responses can always be controlled",
            "used always with other methods (e.g., interviews, performance data, psychophysiological co-recording)",
            "used only in controlled settings (e.g., lab setting)"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "One important design implication of the reading-speaking-listening cognitive system is:",
        "options": [
            "to don't use accentuated intonation of artificially generated speech voices",
            "to use short speech-based menus and instructions",
            "to use fixed text dimensions on screens",
            "to provide up ot 10 options in a speech-based menu"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Referring to the double diamond model of the design, the \"discover phase\" involves:",
        "options": [
            "proposing a solution that works after being evaluated",
            "implementing working prototypes",
            "producing the conceptual model for the product",
            "getting insight into the problem"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Voice and gesture interfaces can be classified as:",
        "options": [
            "natural user interfaces",
            "brain computer interface",
            "sharable interfaces",
            "tangible interfaces"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "An interface metaphor that has become popular in the last few years, especially in social media apps is:",
        "options": [
            "Hyperlinks",
            "Cards",
            "Manipulation",
            "Window, icon, menu, pointer (WIMP)"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The usability goal named \"effectiveness\" refers to:",
        "options": [
            "the way the product supports the user in the task",
            "how good a product is at doing what it is supposed to do",
            "protecting the user from potential dangers",
            "the extent to which the product provides the needed functionalities"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of online questionnaires?",
        "options": [
            "data can be collected in the database for subsequent analysis",
            "errors can be corrected easily",
            "relatively easy and quick to distribute",
            "low drop-out of users"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "User eXperience:",
        "options": [
            "is unrelated to system usability",
            "is related to cultural identity",
            "depends on the researchers",
            "depends on the method employed to assess"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Sentiment analysis:",
        "options": [
            "follows a process similar to thematic analysis",
            "is meant to construct a theory around the phenomenon of interest",
            "aims to identify the objective truth",
            "is a technique that is used to infer the effect of what a group of people is feeling"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "During _________, eyes stop scanning the scene and hold the foveal area of our field of vision in one place",
        "options": [
            "Saccades",
            "Tremors",
            "Smooth pursuit",
            "Fixations"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Technology that overlays digitally created content onto the real world, typically through the use of devices such as smartphones, tablets, or specialized glasses, is called:",
        "options": [
            "Virtual Reality (VR)",
            "Augmented Reality (AR)",
            "VR CAVE",
            "IoT"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Referred to the type of setting chosen for an evaluation study, natural settings involving users:",
        "options": [
            "Show how people use technology in a natural context but are time-consuming and more difficult to conduct.",
            "Reveal usability problems but poorly capture the context of use.",
            "Are time-saving and easy to conduct but make it difficult to capture usability problems.",
            "Are time-saving and easy to conduct but can miss subtle aspects of the user experience."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Examples of robot design patterns include:",
        "options": [
            "Motion pattern, Transform pattern, Initial introduction pattern",
            "Affordance pattern, Initial introduction pattern, Anthropomorphization pattern",
            "Didactic communication pattern, Motion pattern, Initial introduction pattern",
            "Didactic communication pattern, Appearance pattern, Affordance pattern"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Pupil dilatation variation can be caused by:",
        "options": [
            "Saccades velocity, Light, Cognitive load",
            "Light, Saccades frequency, Emotional stimuli",
            "Cognitive load, Emotional stimuli, Light",
            "Overt attention, Light, Cognitive load"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "In the video analysis methodology, ____________ is a list of events of interest within the video",
        "options": [
            "Modifier",
            "State Event",
            "Breakdown",
            "Coding scheme"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "__________ is the degree to which the VR environment surrounds and captivates the user's senses, creating a convincing illusion of reality",
        "options": [
            "Immersion",
            "Social Interaction",
            "Spatial Awareness",
            "Emotional Engagement"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The eye tracking metric \"Time for first fixation (TFF)\" is:",
        "options": [
            "The amount of time that it takes a respondent to look at a specific stimulus",
            "The state in which the gaze remains stationary at a point from 100 to 500 ms",
            "The number of fixations per second",
            "A graphical combination of Fixations and Saccades"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "When all participants perform all the experimental conditions, the experimental design is a:",
        "options": [
            "Within-subject design",
            "Between-subject design",
            "One-tailed design",
            "Two-tailed design"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "In Human-Robot Interaction, the design process that emphasizes the characteristics of the users and the context of use is called:",
        "options": [
            "Industrial robot design",
            "Exploration robot design",
            "Inside-out approach",
            "Outside-in approach"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "In a top-down video analysis:",
        "options": [
            "Events of interest are determined during the analysis",
            "Analyzed videos are less than 10 minutes long",
            "Events of interest are determined a priori",
            "Analyzed videos are longer than 10 minutes"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Dependent variables are:",
        "options": [
            "What the researcher manipulates",
            "Variables that show a positive correlation between them",
            "What the researcher measures",
            "Variables that show a negative correlation between them"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    }
]